<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Christophe Somewhat Techy Website - python</title><link href="https://tofguerrier.github.io/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://tofguerrier.github.io/feeds/python.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://tofguerrier.github.io/</id><updated>2014-10-13T00:05:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>Somewhat Techy Website</subtitle><entry><title>Random thoughts from Pycon Dublin 2014</title><link href="https://tofguerrier.github.io/articles/random-thoughts-from-pycon-dublin-2014.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2014-10-13T00:05:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-13T00:05:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Christophe</name></author><id>tag:tofguerrier.github.io,2014-10-13:/articles/random-thoughts-from-pycon-dublin-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pycon 2014&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I attended my first Pycon in Dublin, Ireland. It is organised by the wonderful crowd of &lt;a href="https://python.ie/"&gt;Python Ireland&lt;/a&gt;, I would actually recommend that you go to one of their monthly meetups if you have any interest in the Python language. !day 2 Main stage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not sure what to expect, but the experience turned out to be truly enjoyable, and I finished up the weekend, my head full of ideas to investigate with python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my favourite highlights of the weekend, in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian Ozsvald &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ianozsvald"&gt;@ianozsvald&lt;/a&gt;  with its talk titled: &lt;a href="http://ianozsvald.com/2014/10/11/my-keynote-at-pyconireland-2014-the-real-unsolved-problems-in-data-science/"&gt;The Real Unsolved Problems in Data Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/saoili"&gt;@saoili&lt;/a&gt; about getting into python jobs, which comfort me in my current chosen path.  See her lightning talk &lt;a href="http://t.co/xTvf1Y2k4e"&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the same lightning talk show, a very entertaining demonstration of failing at data science (Homeless cloud by an engineer from rehabstudios, I sadly forgot the name), but also a silent presentation by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dontusethiscode"&gt;@dontusethiscode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Willmer &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rwillmer"&gt;@rwillmer&lt;/a&gt; in her keynote: A Tech Person's Adventures in Startup, gave me some inspiration and food for thoughts on creating your own company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that Python was widely used in the financial industry (something I did not know before ) thanks to Dr. Yves J. Hilpisch &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dyjh"&gt;@dyjh&lt;/a&gt; keynote : Python and the Financial Industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally a very cool demonstration, inside iPython notebook on how to build an earth centered universe by Brandon Rhodes &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brandon_rhodes"&gt;@brandon_rhodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall it was fun, exciting and energizing conference, I will probably be back next year, more engaged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference happen every year, have a look on the python ireland &lt;a href="https://python.ie"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for more information on Pycon. Also they usually make the presentation available on youtube, see &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCXlA9u2VPI9nIALNUBF0Nzw"&gt;Python Ireland channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2019: Sadly I did not engage more nor attended since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="python"/><category term="Python"/><category term="Ireland"/></entry></feed>